Denver, CO LinkedIn

## Jeff Ruane

yo@jbrr.dev

I'm a software engineer with 5 years of experience working on everything from web development to microservices to ETL pipelines. As an engineer, my focus is solving business needs and creating maintainable, debuggable systems. As a human, I strive to be kind, empathetic, and supportive above all else, and to stay curious.

## **Work Experience**

Senior Software Engineer Tackle.io

Denver, CO

• Handling data ingest from a wide variety of sources in a wide variety of formats

**Senior Software Engineer** 

Uplight

Mar 2020 - Aug 2021

Dec 2021 – present

Data Ingest team

Data team

Denver, CO

- Led a team of 3 engineers in defining and designing a new data warehouse to serve the rest of the company with the data that drives customer-facing products, as well as exposing data back to the client in a structured format, launching an important new client on time on the new platform.
- Focused on ETL pipelines in and out of the warehouse and designing a validation framework to prevent malformed data from going downstream, processing 10s of millions of rows of complex data per day.
- Mentored younger engineers in diagnosing data issues, freeing up significant bandwidth for senior staff.
- Collaborated with business and product stakeholders to examine what data we need from new clients and the format it should be in, avoiding costly mistakes and preserving timelines.

**Software Engineer**Data Ingest team
Uplight
Denver, CO

Jul 2019 – Mar 2020

- Developed and shipped a new event-driven, modular ETL pipeline for utility billing and usage data resulting in a 15% 30% decrease in the time required to ingest data for a new client.
- Developed an on-call schedule for my team to handle a large operational workload to prevent burnout.
- Owned the most profitable product at the company and was the go-to resource for operations teams that were running into issues, new engineers looking for guidance on how to make changes, and the customer success team trying to launch new clients on time.

Software Engineer Tendril 2016 – 2019

**Customer Engineering team** 

Boulder, CO

- Owned the authentication integration between the web portal and new clients, including daily standups and debugging sessions with the client's IT team, sand managed around-the-clock support during go live.
- Internationalized a web portal application allowing the company to launch a program in Italy, and opened the doors for more international deals, and gave the sales team an exciting new logo to use.

## **Technologies and Language**

Languages: Python, Ruby, JavaScript, Java, Scala

Technologies: Postgres, AWS, GCS, Airflow, Spark, Beam, Redshift, Big Query
 Other: ETL, event-driven architecture, relational databases, debugging

## **Education and Certifications**

Backend Engineering, Turing School of Software & Design, Denver.

Philosophy, University of Colorado, Boulder.

2015 - 2016 2004 - 2009